Woobin Im

⊯임우빈 Ph.D. candidate SGVR Lab @ KAIST in linkedin.com/in/woobin-im

★ 402V_I8AAAAJ

github.com/iwbn

niwbn.github.io/

About

I'm a Ph.D. candidate at KAIST, South Korea. My research is focused on solving **computer vision** problems using **machine learning**. I am especially interested in **motion**, so I have been working on video-related topics.

Research interests: video, optical flow, spacetime, dynamic NeRF, generative models.

Award

- Naver Ph.D Fellowship Award, 2022.
- Finalist at Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship Korea (QIFK), 2020.
- Outstanding Teaching Assistant Award (우수조교상), KAIST, 2019.

Education

• KAIST, Ph.D., Computer Science 2018-current

Advisor: Professor Sung-Eui Yoon

• KAIST, M.S., Computer Science 2016-2018

Advisor: Professor Hyun Seung Yang

• Yonsei University, B.S., Computer Science 2012-2016

Work

• CLOVA, NAVER Cloud Corp. (internship) 2023.02-2023.08

Service

• SGVR KAIST Website (Skill: web frontend, Wordpress, PHP) 2018-current

• GPU Cluster (Skill: Docker, Kubernetes, Grafana) 2023-current

Publication

Regularizing Dynamic Radiance Fields with Kinematic Fields
 Woobin Im, Geonho Cha, Sebin Lee, Juhyeong Seon, Jumin Lee, Dongyoon Wee, and Sung-Eui Yoon
 European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2024
 [To appear]

• Fine-grained Background Representation for Weakly Supervised Semantic Segmentation

Xu Yin, **Woobin Im**, Dongbo Min, Yuchi Huo, Fei Pan, and Sung-Eui Yoon *IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology (TCSVT)*, 2024 [arxiv] [web] [github]

 Extending Segment Anything Model into Auditory and Temporal Dimensions for Audio-Visual Segmentation

Juhyeong Seon, **Woobin Im**, Sebin Lee, Jumin Lee, and Sung-Eui Yoon *International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP)*, 2024 [arxiv] [github]

• SemCity: Semantic Scene Generation with Triplane Diffusion

Jumin Lee*, Sebin Lee*, Changho Jo, **Woobin Im**, Ju-hyeong Seon, and Sung-Eui Yoon

Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2024 *Equal contribution [arxiv] [web] [github]

- Multi-resolution distillation for self-supervised monocular depth estimation Sebin Lee, Woobin Im, and Sung-Eui Yoon Pattern Recognition Letters, 2023
- Diffusion Probabilistic Models for Scene-Scale 3D Categorical Data
 Jumin Lee, Woobin Im, Sebin Lee, and Sung-Eui Yoon
 Workshop on Image Processing and Image Understanding (IPIU), 2023
 Best Paper Award [arxiv] [github]
- Scenario Generation by Action Scene-Graph Prediction Woobin Im, Woo Jae Kim, and Sung-Eui Yoon Korea Software Congress (KSC), 2022 [web] [paper]

Semi-Supervised Learning of Optical Flow by Flow Supervisor

Woobin Im, Sebin Lee, and Sung-Eui Yoon *European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)*, 2022 [web] [arxiv] [github]

• In-N-Out: Towards Good Initialization for Inpainting and Outpainting

Changho Jo, **Woobin Im**, and Sung-Eui Yoon *British Machine Vision Conference (BMVC)*, 2021 [web] [arxiv] [github]

• Self-Supervised Visual Odometry via Frame Interpolation

Sebin Lee, **Woobin Im**, and Sung-Eui Yoon *Korea Robotics Society Annual Conference (KRoC)*, 2021 [paper]

Unsupervised Learning of Optical Flow with Deep Feature Similarity

Woobin Im, Tae-Kyun Kim, and Sung-Eui Yoon *European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)*, 2020 [web] [paper] [github]

Combined Center Dispersion Loss Function for Deep Facial Expression Recognition

Abhilasha Nanda, **Woobin Im**, Key-Sun Choi, and Hyun Seung Yang *Pattern Recognition Letters*, 2020 [paper]

Two-stream Spatiotemporal Feature for Video QA Task

Chiwan Song, **Woobin Im**, and Sung-Eui Yoon *https://arxiv.org/abs/1907.05006*, 2019 [arxiv]

• Acoustic Material Estimation with Convolutional Neural Network

Doheon Lee, Inkyu An, **Woobin Im**, and Sung-Eui Yoon *Korea Robotics Society Annual Conference (KRoC)*, 2019 [paper]

An Application of Convolutional-LSTM Network and Video QA

Chiwan Song, **Woobin Im**, and Sung-Eui Yoon *Korea Computer Congress (KCC)*, 2018 [paper]

 Scale-Varying Triplet Ranking with Classification Loss for Facial Age Estimation Woobin Im, Sungeun Hong, Sung-Eui Yoon, and Hyun S. Yang Asian Conference on Computer Vision (ACCV), 2018
 [web] [paper] [github]

• CBVMR: Content-Based Video-Music Retrieval Using Soft Intra-Modal Structure Constraint

Sungeun Hong, **Woobin Im**, and Hyun S. Yang *Proceedings of the ACM international conference on Multimedia Retrieval (ICMR)*,

2018

[paper] [video]

• D3: Recognizing dynamic scenes with deep dual descriptor based on key frames and key segments

Sungeun Hong, Jongbin Ryu, **Woobin Im**, and Hyun S. Yang *Neurocomputing*, 2018 [paper]

• SSPP-DAN: Deep Domain Adaptation Network for Face Recognition with Single Sample Per Person

Sungeun Hong, **Woobin Im**, Jongbin Ryu, and Hyun S. Yang *International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP'17), IEEE*, 2017 **Oral** [paper]

- Convolutional Texture Networks based on Histogram Pooling Jongbin Ryu, Sungeun Hong, Woobin Im, and Hyun S. Yang
- Image-text multi-modal representation learning by adversarial backpropagation

Gwangbeen Park and **Woobin Im** *arXiv preprint arXiv:1612.08354*, 2016

Deep CNN-based Person Identification using Facial and Clothing Features
 Sungeun Hong, Woobin Im, Junwoo Park, and Hyun S. Yang
 Jun 2016, Summer General Conference '16, IEEK, 2016

Patent

- 트리플릿 기반의 손실함수를 활용한 순서가 있는 분류문제를 위한 딥러닝 모델 학습 방법 및 장치 (Using Triplet-based Loss for Training Ordinal Classification Deep Models)
 [US App] [KR App]
- 부분 이미지 기반 객체 판별 방법 및 장치 (Partial Face Based Person Identification

Across Poses)
[KR]

- 도메인 적응 기반 객체 인식 모델 제공 장치 및 방법 (APPARATUS AND METHOD FOR PROVIDING OBJECT RECOGNITION MODEL BASED ON DOMAIN ADAPTATION)
 [KR App]
- 광학 흐름 추정을 위한 딥 유사도 기반 비지도 학습의 컴퓨터 시스템 및 그의 방법 (COMPUTER SYSTEM OF UNSUPERVISED LEARNING WITH DEEP SIMILARITY FOR OPTICAL FLOW ESTIMATION AND METHOD THEREOF)
 [KR] [US App]

Experience

- Teaching Assistants
 - o GSAG-KAIST Research and Education Program, 1/2019-2/2019
 - CS206: Data Structure (Spring 2019), 3/2019-6/2019
 - CS688: Web-Scale Image Retrieval (Fall 2018), 9/2018-12/2018
 - o CS101: Introduction to Programming, 9/2016-12/2017, 9/2018-12/2018
- Undergraduate Research Assistant
 - o DB Lab, Yonsei University, 1/2014-2/2014